{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Hydrogen bonds in a-helices are", "opta": "more numerous than Vander Waals interactions", "optb": "not present at Phe residues", "optc": "analogous to the steps in a spiral staircase", "optd": "roughly parallel to the helix axis", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The peptide bond in proteins is", "opta": "only found between proline residues", "optb": "usually cis unless proline is the next amino acid", "optc": "usually trans unless proline is the next amino acid", "optd": "is planar because of steric hinderance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The molecular formula for glycine is C2H5O2N. What would be the molecular formula for a linear oligomer made by linking ten glycine molecules together by condensation synthesis?", "opta": "C20H50O20N10", "optb": "C20H32O11N10", "optc": "C20H40O10N10", "optd": "C20H68O29N10", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an example of tertiary structure in a protein?", "opta": "A multimeric protein", "optb": "An a-helix", "optc": "A P-pleated sheet", "optd": "A globular domain", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The peptide, Val-Lys-Glu-Met-Ser-Trp-Arg-Ala, was digested with cyanogen bromide (CNBr) to produce:", "opta": "Val-Lys + Glu-Met-Ser + Trp-Arg-Ala", "optb": "Val-Lys-Glu-Met-Ser-Trp + Arg-Ala", "optc": "Val-Lys-Glu-Met + Ser-Trp-Arg-Ala", "optd": "Val-Lys-Glu + Met-Ser-Trp-Arg-Ala", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In deoxy hemoglobin (Hb), the Fe (II) is coordinated to", "opta": "four nitrogens of heme, the proximal His, and a water molecule", "optb": "four nitrogens of heme and to a water molecule", "optc": "two nitrogens of heme and to three His residues in Hb", "optd": "two nitrogens of heme and to three water molecules", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the \u03b2-pleated sheet", "opta": "hydrogen bonds are formed between the peptide bonds", "optb": "adjacent polypeptide chains can either be parallel or antiparallel", "optc": "the polypeptide chain is fully extended", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Ramachandran Plot illustrates the fact that", "opta": "the peptide bond is planar", "optb": "the F & Y angles can assume any value in a peptide", "optc": "the F & Y angles can assume only a single value in a protein", "optd": "the F & Y angles can assume approximately three different values", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The resonance structures that can be drawn for the peptide bond indicate that the peptide bond", "opta": "is stronger than an ordinary single bond", "optb": "has partial double bond character", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "is still not completely understood", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The major element of secondary structure in myoglobin and hemoglobin is", "opta": "the P-strand", "optb": "the a-helix", "optc": "the reverse turn", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An oil drop with a polar coat is a metaphor referring to the three dimensional structure of", "opta": "fibrous proteins", "optb": "collagen", "optc": "globular proteins", "optd": "silk protein", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What was the first protein whose complete tertiary structure was determined?", "opta": "Lysozyme", "optb": "Myoglobin", "optc": "Pancreatic ribonuclease", "optd": "Pancreatic DNase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The peptide bond in proteins is", "opta": "planar, but rotates to three preferred dihedral angles", "optb": "nonpolar, but rotates to three preferred dihedral angles", "optc": "nonpolar, and fixed in a trans conformation", "optd": "planar, and usually found in a trans conformation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In \u03b2-pleated sheet structures neighbouring", "opta": "chains lie in a flat plane", "optb": "neighboring residues are hydrogen bonded", "optc": "neighboring chains are connected by a-helices", "optd": "neighboring chains are hydrogen bonded", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The same peptide, Val-Lys-Glu-Met-Ser-Trp-Arg-Ala. was digested with chymotrypsin to produce", "opta": "Val-Lys + Glu-Met-Ser + Trp-Arg-Ala.", "optb": "Val-Lys-Glu-Met-Ser-Trp + Arg-Ala.", "optc": "Val-Lys-Glu-Met-Ser + Trp-Arg-Ala.", "optd": "Val-Lys-Glu-Met + Ser-Trp-Arg-Ala.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Disulfide bonds most often stabilize the native structure of", "opta": "extracellular proteins", "optb": "dimeric proteins", "optc": "hydrophobic proteins", "optd": "intracellular proteins", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Secondary structure in protein refers to", "opta": "linear sequence of amino acids joined together by peptide bond", "optb": "three dimensional arrangement of all amino acids in polypeptide chain", "optc": "regular folding of regions of the polypeptide chain", "optd": "protein made up of more than one polypeptide chain", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Heme is the binding pocket of myoglobin and hemoglobin and is composed of", "opta": "negatively charged residues", "optb": "polar residues", "optc": "hydrophobic residues", "optd": "positively charged residues", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the effect of a decrease in pH on hemoglobin oxygen affinity?", "opta": "Decrease in oxygen affinity", "optb": "Increase in oxygen affinity", "optc": "No effect on oxygen affinity", "optd": "Increase affinity in muscle cell otherwise decrease", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the proportion of glycine residues in collagenous regions?", "opta": "One-fourth", "optb": "One-third", "optc": "Half", "optd": "One-tenth", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is incorrect?", "opta": "Protein G contains both a-helix and P-sheet", "optb": "Protein G contains only a-helix", "optc": "Fatty acid binding protein contains largely P-sheet", "optd": "Hemoglobin contains four sub-units", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oxygen binding curves of hemoglobin and myoglobin", "opta": "allow maximum transfer of oxygen to the tissues", "optb": "are a consequence of the quaternary structure of hemoglobin", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "are identical", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nature of peptide bond can be best explained as", "opta": "partial double bond", "optb": "truly double bond", "optc": "Hydrogen bond", "optd": "Van der waals force", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect?", "opta": "Hemoglobin and myoglobin are the two oxygen binding proteins", "optb": "Hemoglobin transports O2 in the blood", "optc": "Myoglobin stores O2 in muscles", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which hemoglobin chain replaces the beta chain in embryonic hemoglobulin?", "opta": "Delta", "optb": "Epsilon", "optc": "Gamma", "optd": "Alfa", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hemoglobin has quaternary structure and is made up of", "opta": "six polypeptide chains, two \u03b1-chains and four \u03b2-chains", "optb": "two polypeptide chains, one \u03b1-chains and one \u03b2-chains", "optc": "four polypeptide chains, two \u03b1-chains and two \u03b2-chains", "optd": "five polypeptide chains, two \u03b1-chains and three \u03b2-chains", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When pO2 = Kd of myoglobin, the fractional saturation (YO2) is about", "opta": "0.1", "optb": "0.5", "optc": "0.9", "optd": "1.7", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Peptides in the fully extended chain conformation", "opta": "have Y = F = 180\u00b0", "optb": "do not occur in nature", "optc": "also have a cis geometry in their peptide bonds", "optd": "are equivalent to the (3-sheet structure", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oxygen in hemoglobin and myoglobin is bound to", "opta": "the iron atom in the heme group", "optb": "the nitrogen atoms on the heme", "optc": "histidine residues in the protein", "optd": "lysine residues in the protein", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the three subunits of the G proteins binds GDP and GTP?", "opta": "Alpha", "optb": "Beta", "optc": "Gamma", "optd": "Delta", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the F and Y angles of each peptide unit in a protein are known, which of the following may also be determined?", "opta": "Complete secondary structure", "optb": "Complete tertiary structure", "optc": "Complete quaternary structure", "optd": "Thermodynamic stability", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The different orders of protein structure are determined by all of the following bond types except", "opta": "peptide bonds", "optb": "phospho-diester bonds", "optc": "disulfide bridges", "optd": "hydrogen bonds", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heme is held in place by a bond between", "opta": "the Fe2+ and cysteine", "optb": "the Fe3+ and histidine", "optc": "the Fe3+ and cysteine", "optd": "the Fe2+ and histidine", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}